Giles Barber

Front-end web developer

- London, UK
- 07749 117 410
- gilesbarber@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/gilesbarber



GitHub portfolio

Summary

Creative front-end web developer specialising in interactives. A fun packed decade of experience in e-learning and EdTech under my belt. I love bringing online learning to life using interactive assets and gamification concepts that help the user retain key learning points. Passionate about gamification, accessibility, semantics and using Web Standards to deliver an intuitive experience to the user.

Technical skills

HTML5 • CSS3 • SCSS • JavaScript • jQuery • React • JSON

- Git Webpack NPM Wordpress Hubspot SharePoint
- Thought Industries Moodle Evolve H5P SCORM
- Adobe Creative Cloud Asana

Experience

Interactive Developer | Avado | London

Jun 2018 - present

- Worked on e-learning platform utilising an agile model with weekly sprints
- Involved in launching five new online courses including apprenticeships, Professional Qualifications & Google's Digital Marketing Course
- Built interactives using React along with relevant web technologies.
- Developed 30 new interactives including 12 gamified quizzes - accessible to WCAG 2.1 standards
- Collaborated on deployment of company brand refresh and internal brand launch of LightBox Studio
- Developed UI skills and general creative process through weekly design crit

Web Producer | The Invisible Orthodontist | London

Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

- Managed new website builds as well as ongoing development projects for 35 clients in a fast-paced agency providing full service consultancy to orthodontist practices in the UK, Australia and the US
- Delivered a workshop for 20 clients on the benefits of online reputation management and how to deliver content through social media channels

Web Project Coordinator | Oxford University Press | Oxford

May 2011 - Oct 2017

- Coded and launched over 20 ELT student websites
- Developed new games templates using HTML5, JavaScript and JSON
- Key role in the OUP Mexico website in the local market, travelling to Mexico City to train the in-house team on how to develop the site using the CMS

Education

BSc (Hons) Publishing with Anthropology. 2:1 Oxford Brookes University, 2004 -2008

- ePublishing
- Research methods
- Content, Design and Technology-(Design theory and application using Adobe Creative Suite),
- Dissertation in Design and web usability

Oxford University, Department for Continuing Education, 2014 -2015

Courses:

- Intermediate Web Design and Development
- Responsive Web Design and Development
- JavaScript

Personal Skills

- Communicating technical concepts
- Problem solving
- Coordinating multiple projects concurrently
- Generating ideas during Agile sprint planning